Isaac Taft Stoddard papers, 1890-1943
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Isaac Taft Stoddard papers, 1890-1943
AZ 148
Stoddard, Isaac Taft
Correspondence, legal papers, financial records, maps, and geologists' reports related to the Stoddard Copper Company and Copper Mountains Mines Company in Yavapai County, Arizona; records of the Stoddard Incorporating Company and its dealings with mining firms; and a scrapbook of photographs of mine construction and operations. Includes materials on Arizona economy and politics.
3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Arizona businessman and politician; Secretary of Arizona Territory, 1901 to 1904.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, legal papers, financial records, maps, and geologists' reports related to the Stoddard Copper Company and Copper Mountains Mines Company in Yavapai County, Arizona; records of the Stoddard Incorporating Company and its dealings with mining firms; and a scrapbook of photographs of mine construction and operations. Includes materials on Arizona economy and politics. Materials from Isaac's son, Celora Martin Stoddard, include personal and business papers, stories and sketches, papers concerning the Great Western Firm Corporation, and a photograph album from his school days. Also included is a 1902 diary by Isaac's daughter, Florence. Note: Material in Volumes 8, 9, and 10 are a selected representation of the business carried on by the Stoddard Incorporting Company. Lesser, routine and fragmentary accounts were not retained.
Access Terms
Stoddard, Isaac Taft -- 1851-1914
Stoddard, Celora Martin -- 1886-1943
Stoddard, Florence, -- 1881-1903 -- Diaries
Arizona Binghamton Copper Company -- Records and correspondence
Stoddard Incorporating Company -- Records and correspondence
Copper Mountain Mines Company -- Records and correspondence
Stoddard Copper Company -- Records and correspondence
Great Western Film Corporation
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Yavapai County -- History -- Sources
Copper mines and mining -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mineral industries -- Arizona -- Finance -- Sources
Mining corporations -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Stoddard (Ariz.) -- History -- Sources
Arizona -- Politics and government -- Sources
Account books
Photoprints
Photographs
Diaries
Correspondence
Container List
- Finding Aid to the collection. (Volume 1)
- Stoddard, Isaac Taft: Miscellaneous Personal Papers (family records, correspondence and papers relating to his position as Territorial Secretary). 1894-1913 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Stoddard, Isaac Taft: Newspaper Clippings. 1911-1913 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Marshall S. Taft. undated. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Stoddard Copper Company: Legal Papers. 1898-1906. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Stoddard Copper Company: Misc. Papers, Photos, Etc. 1901-1907. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Stoddard Copper Company (and others): Notices of Mining Locations, Deeds, Etc. No Date (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Geologists' Reports. undated. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Receipts for Mail Service: Stoddard, Arizona to Humboldt, Arizona; Stoddard, Arizona to Mayer, Arizona. 1912-1918 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence Regarding Labor and Strikes: James Douglas to I.T. Stoddard, Celora M. Stoddard to Barr Agency, Celora M. Stoddard to Burns Detective Agency. 1903, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Arizona Binghampton Copper Company Papers. 1915-1919 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Copper Mountain Mines Company: Stockholders. Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Copper Mountain Mines Company: Legal Papers (articles of incorporation, bylaws). 1917-1929 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Copper Mountain Mines Company: Correspondence. 1920-1923 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Copper Mountain Mines Company: Financial Papers. 1917-1919, 1922-1923, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Copper Mountain Mines Company: Correspondence & Financial Papers. 1931-1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Includes:
  Stock Journal and Ledger, 1917-1929
  Minutes of board of Directors, 1917-1926
  Harvey, Henry: Harvey's Mining Code, NY, 1889
- Scrapbook of Photographs: Mine Construction and Operation at Stoddard, Arizona (includes pictures of I.T. Stoddard, Celora M. Stoddard and other mine workers). 1916 (Volume 4)
- Mineral Patents and Maps: Seven Mineral Patents and 21 Maps of Stoddard Mine Property, Agua Fria Mining District, Yavapai County, Arizona. No Date (Volume 5)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Miscellaneous Papers. 1904-1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Minute Book and Ledger, 1904-1940
  Where and How to Incorporate in Arizona, published by the Stoddard Incorporating Company, Phoenix, No Date
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Arizona Corporation Commission: Audit no.1. July 1, 1933-March 31, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Assorted Stock Certificates and Book of Cancelled Stock Certificates. Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Celora Martin Stoddard, Personal Papers and Correspondence (photographs and biographical material). 1903-1919 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Photo Scrapbook: School years and Photos of Stoddard Mines, 1903-1907
- Celora Martin Stoddard: Stories and Sketches. Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Celora Martin Stoddard: Serial Story: "Jane-the Gum Model." Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Celora Martin Stoddard: Novel: "There's a Stain." Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Celora Martin Stoddard: Great Western Film Corporation-Correspondence and Legal Papers. 1917-1919 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
- Celora Martin Stoddard: Inventions of C.M. Stoddard: Postage Stamp Stamping Machine; Improvement in Logometers; Route Indicators for Automobiles. 1901, 1914, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Big Jim Mine-Correspondence. 1936-1938 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Deriick Mining Company-Correspondence. 1936-1942 (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Columbia Metal Mines Company-Articles of Incorporation, 1936-1943 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Columbia Metal Mines Company-Correspondence. 1936-1943 (Box 9, Folder 2-5)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Columbia Metal Mines Company-Stock Journal and Ledger. Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Columbia Metal Mines Company-Stockholders; Miscellaneous Papers. Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Correspondence. 1938-1942 (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Bills and Receipts. Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Old Dominion Papers. Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Legal Papers. Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Pay Rolls. Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Workmen's Compensation Papers. Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Stoddard Incorporating Company: Miscellaneous Reports. Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)